Calgary, Alberta (403) 312-4690

iryna.tar18@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/iryna-tarasenko

Portfolio: https://iryna-portfolio.netlify.app/

Iryna Tarasenko

I am a motivated, passionate and well-organized web developer with a high sense of responsibility and the ability to meet deadlines. On the one hand, I am experienced working in a team to achieve the best result. On the other hand, I'm not afraid to take responsibility and solve problems by researching solutions. And what really differentiates me is my attention to details and time-management skills.

PRIMARY SKILLS

- JavaScript, Angular, React.js, SQL, mySql, typeORM, Node.js, jQuery, HTML, CSS, SCSS, Bootstrap, Angular Material UI
- SCRUM, Agile
- GitHub, Bitbucket
- Mac OS, Linux

SECONDARY SKILLS

- Express.js, Python, MongoDB
- Postgres, Firebase

EXPERIENCE

Rappid Software Design Inc, Software Developer October 2021- current
Blue Mountains, ON, Canada

- Increased loading speed by optimizing queries, re-writed queries to raw sql/query builder in some critical parts of the application
- Improved email notifications by implementing dynamic links to add ability to redirect users to mobile app.
- Implemented angular component to create reusable accordion select functionality
- Developed dashboard with dynamic data in charts and graphs using Ngx-Charts, d3
- Modified google cloud functions to add PDF report generation
- Created new modules and refactored UI and backend to increase performance of page loading

Technologies: Angular, Node.js, mySQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, typeORM, Firebase, Angular Material, HTML, CSS

EvolveU, Full Stack web developer/intern

May 2021- September 2021 Calgary, AB, Canada

- Developed authentication module which helps users to login and make online payment for water sport activity
 - Technologies: React, CSS, JavaScript, MongoDB, Express.js, Stripe
- Developed mobile-friendly landing page for CanBudget app https://canbudget.herokuapp.com/, implemented custom routes to allow users to scroll to specific target on the page

Technologies: React, JavaScript, React styled components

EvolveU, Full Stack web developer/intern

March 2021-April 2021 Calgary, AB, Canada

- Developed text-based game "Choose your own adventure"
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, EJS, MongoDB, Express.js

Code the Change YYC, Full Stack web developer/intern

September 2020-November 2020 Calgary, AB, Canada

- Developed authentication module which helps users to login and booking computers for non-profit organization
- Worked in a team of three developers and participated in code reviews to provide schedule for meetings between mentors and students
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.is, Firebase(Firestore)

Women in Technology Program, Making **Changes Association,** Intern

April 2020 - September 2020 Calgary, AB, Canada

- Developed integration with Stripe API to provide online payments for dance classes(Abhinaya Dance Studio)
- Developed integration with Zapier API to notify students and dance studio management about payments
- Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Stripe, Firebase, Zapier

State Enterprise Scientific and Production Complex of April 2008 - March 2019 Gas Turbine Building "Zorya", **Design Engineer**

Nikolaev, Ukraine

 Redesigned molds for technical components and units for gas turbines. Improved mold lifetime for 1.5 times due to cooling system improvements

- Participated in supervision, adjusting and testing in collaboration with other specialists molds to receive a molds of the required quality
- Identified and solved problems during initial production of new product design, participated in design discussions, leading to optimized solution to projects

EDUCATION

EvolveU, InceptionU Ltd -	March 2021 - September 2021
Full Stack Web Developer	Calgary, AB, Canada
Women in Technology Program, Making Changes	April 2020 - November 2020
Association - Full Stack Web Developer	Calgary, AB, Canada
Admiral Makarov National University of Shipbuilding - MS, Finance	October 2008 - November 2010 Nikolaev, Ukraine
Admiral Makarov National University of Shipbuilding - MS, Mechanical Engineer	September 2002 - March 2008 Nikolaev, Ukraine